[
    {
    "question":"Which of the following is an invalid if-else statement?",
    "optionA":"if( if ( a == 1 ) ) { }",
    "optionB":"if ( func1 ( a ) ) { }",
    "optionC":"if ( a ) { }",
    "optionD":"if ( ( char ) a ) { }",
    "answer":"if( if ( a == 1 ) ) { }"
    },

    {
        "question": "The C code 'for(;;)' represents an infinte loop. It can be terminated by _________",
        "optionA": "break",
        "optionB": "exit(0)",
        "optionC": "abort()",
        "optionD": "terminate",
        "answer": "break"
    },

    {
        "question": "Which of the following cannot be used as LHS of the expression in for (exp1;exp2; exp3)? ",
        "optionA": "variable",
        "optionB": " function",
        "optionC": "typedef",
        "optionD": " macros",
        "answer": " macros"
    },

    {
        "question": " Which keyword is used to come out of a loop only for that iteration? ",
        "optionA": "break",
        "optionB": "return",
        "optionC": "continue",
        "optionD": "none of the mentioned",
        "answer":  "continue"
    },

    {
        "question": "What is an example of iteration in C?",
        "optionA": "for",
        "optionB": " while",
        "optionC": "do-while",
        "optionD": "all of the mentioned",
        "answer": "all of the mentioned"
    },

    {
        "question": " Which loop is most suitable to first perform the operation and then test the condition?",
        "optionA": "for loop ",
        "optionB": "do-while loop",
        "optionC": " while loop",
        "optionD": "none of the mentioned",
        "answer": "do-while loop"
    },

    {
        "question": "The keyword ‘break’ cannot be simply used within _________",
        "optionA": "do-while",
        "optionB": "if-else",
        "optionC": "for",
        "optionD": "while",
        "answer": "if-else"
    },

    {
        "question": "Which keyword can be used for coming out of recursion?",
        "optionA": "break",
        "optionB": "return",
        "optionC": "exit",
        "optionD": "both break and return",
        "answer": "return"
    },
    

    {
        "question": "goto can be used to jump from main() to within a function.",
        "optionA": "true",
        "optionB": "false",
        "optionC": "depends",
        "optionD": "varies",
        "answer":  "false"
    },
    
    {
        "question": "Choose a right C Statement.",
    
        "optionA": "Loops or Repetition block executes a group of statements repeatedly.",
        "optionB": "Loops usually take advantage of Loop Counter",
        "optionC": "Loop is usually executed as long as a condition is met.",
        "optionD": " All the above.",
        "answer":  " All the above."
    }

  
]